William Carey Crane papers, Inclusive: 1809-1944, Bulk: 1834-1885
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- General Correspondence, 1832-1885, undated; 1
  - General, 1876 June 12-26 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - General, 1876 June 28-July 15 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - General, 1876 July 18-August 15 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - General, 1876 August 16-30 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - General, 1876 August 30-September 11 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - General, 1876 September 12-25 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - General, 1876 September 27-October (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - General, 1876 November-December 2 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - General, 1876 December 2-26 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - General, 1877 January 1-18 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - General, 1877 January 18-31 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - General, 1877 February (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - General, 1877 March 1-19 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - General, 1877 March 19-April 7 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - General, 1877 April 8-30 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - General, 1877 May-June 2 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - General, 1877 June 10-27 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - General, 1877 June 30-July (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - General, 1877 August (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - General, 1877 September-October (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - General, 1877 November-December 5 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - General, 1877 December 11-26 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - General, 1877 December 26-1878 January 23 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - General, 1878 January 24-February (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - General, 1878 March 1-20 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - General, 1878 March 22-31 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - General, 1878 April 2-10 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - General, 1878 April 12-25 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - General, 1878 April 25-May 20 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - General, 1878 May 21-June 15 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - General, 1878 June 25-29 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - General, 1878 July 1-27 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - General, 1878 July 30-August 10 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - General, 1878 August 10-21 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - General, 1878 August 21-September 6 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - General, 1878 September 7-19 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - General, 1878 September 20-October 23 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - General, 1878 October 25-November 9 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - General, 1878 November 10-29 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - General, 1878 November 22-December (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - General, 1879 January 1-11 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - General, 1879 January 11-20 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - General, 1879 January 20-26 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - General, 1879 January 26-February 8 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - General, 1879 February 9-15 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - General, 1879 February 15-26 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - General, 1879 March 1-17 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - General, 1879 March 18-April 15 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - General, 1879 April 18-June 6 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - General, 1879 June 16-July 12 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - General, 1879 July 17-August 18 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - General, 1879 August 18-September 16 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - General, 1879 September 18-29 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - General, 1879 October-November 6 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - General, 1879 November 6-19 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - General, 1879 November 20-December 8 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - General, 1879 December 8-1880 January 6 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - General, 1880 January 7-February 8 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - General, 1880 February 10-29 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - General, 1880 March-April 18 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - General, 1880 April 19-June 7 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - General, 1880 June 8-July 23 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - General, 1880 July 23-August 21 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - General, 1880 August 27-September (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - General, 1880 October 2-25 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - General, 1880 October 25-November 3 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - General, 1880 November 4-18 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - General, 1880 November 19-December 2 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - General, 1880 December 2-15 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - General, 1880 December 15-31 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - General, 1881 January 1-6 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - General, 1881 January 6-18 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - General, 1881 January 20-31 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - General, 1881 February 1-10 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - General, 1881 February 10-22 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - General, 1881 February 22-March 7 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - General, 1881 March 7-25 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - General, 1881 March 26-April 4 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - General, 1881 April 4-19 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - General, 1881 April 19-May 11 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - General, 1881 May 12-26 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - General, 1881 May 20-June 9 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - General, 1881 June 9-18 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - General, 1881 June 20-July 10 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - General, 1881 July 11-August 13 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - General, 1881 August 13-29 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - General, 1881 August 30-September 5 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - General, 1881 September 5-17 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - General, 1881 September 19-October 13 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - General, 1881 October 14-25 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - General, 1881 October 25-November 2 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - General, 1881 November 3-20 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - General, 1881 November 21-December 11 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - General, 1881 December 12-20 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - General, 1881 December 20-29 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - General, 1881 December 29-1882 January 4 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - General, 1882 January 5-16 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - General, 1882 January 17-24 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - General, 1882 January 25-February 4 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - General, 1882 February 5-21 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - General, 1882 February 22-March 5 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - General, 1882 March 6-20 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - General, 1882 March 20-28 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - General, 1882 April-May 7 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - General, 1882 May 9-June 5 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - General, 1882 June 6-22 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - General, 1882 June 23-July 8 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - General, 1882 July 8-28 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - General, 1882 July 28-August 15 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - General, 1882 August 18-September (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - General, 1882 October 1-23 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - General, 1882 October 26-November (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - General, 1882 December 1-18 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - General, 1882 December 18-30 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - General, 1883 January 2-20 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - General, 1883 January 22-February 8 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - General, 1883 February 9-19 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - General, 1883 February 21-March 3 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - General, 1883 March 3-18 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - General, 1883 March 20-31 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - General, 1883 April (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - General, 1883 May-November 10 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - General, 1883 November 10-29 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - General, 1883 December (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - General, 1884 January-March (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - General, 1884 April-June (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - General, 1884 September-October 22 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - General, 1884 October 23-November 16 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - General, 1884 November 17-December (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - General, 1885 January 1-14 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - General, 1885 January 16-February 9 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - General, 1885 February 9-March (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - General: (1 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - General: (2 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - General: (3 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - General: (4 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - General: (5 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - General: (6 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - General: (7 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - General: (8 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - General: (9 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - General: (10 of 10), undated (Box 21, Folder 18)
- Personal Correspondence, 1833-1944, undated; 2
  General condition: Poor.
  This series contains William Carey Crane’s correspondence with various individuals, universities, and conventions.
  - George Adams, S.T. Anderson, and R.E.B. Baylor, 1867-1944 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Bible Revision Convention: Memphis, 1845-1852 June (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Bible Revision Convention: Memphis, 1852 July-1854 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Bible Revision Convention: Memphis, 1855-1856 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - Bible Revision Convention: Memphis, 1857-1859 (Box 21, Folder 23)
  - H.F. Buckner and Richard Burleson, 1846-1875 (Box 21, Folder 24)
  - Rufus Burleson, 1845-1875 February (Box 21, Folder 25)
  - Rufus Burleson, 1875 March-1878 August (Box 21, Folder 26)
  - Rufus Burleson, 1878 September-1882, undated (Box 21, Folder 27)
  - L.E.F. Denig, John Dorsett, and Maria Dorsett, 1862-1876 (Box 21, Folder 28)
  - Fayette County, 1840-1846 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Fayette County, 1880-1885 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Hosea Garrett, W.S. Graves, Nettie Houston, Nellie Kelley, 1865-1884 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Russel Holman, 1847-1849 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - A.J. Lowndes, 1866-1886 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Presidency: Mississippi College, 1846-1851 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Presidency: Mississippi College, 1852-1854 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Presidency: Mississippi College, 1855-1859 May 24 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Presidency: Mississippi College, 1859 May 25-June (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - M.W. Philips, 1849-1850 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - M.W. Philips, 1851-1852 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - M.W. Philips, 1853-1854 August (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - M.W. Philips, 1854 December-1857 April (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - M.W. Philips, 1857 June-1859 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - William Remington, John Smith, Baron Stow, and Charles Webb, 1836-1868 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Henry van Senness, 1832-1833 October (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Henry van Senness, 1833 December-1835 February (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Henry van Senness, 1835 June-1839 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - University of Mississippi, 1848-1852 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - University of Mississippi, 1853-1856 August (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - University of Mississippi, 1856 September-1857 October (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - University of Mississippi, 1857 November-1858 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - University of Mississippi, 1859-1867 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Transcripts: University of Texas Archives, 1846-1859 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Transcripts: University of Texas Archives, 1871 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Transcripts: University of Texas Archives, 1872 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Transcripts: University of Texas Archives, 1873-1874 April (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Transcripts: University of Texas Archives, 1874 May-December (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - Transcripts: University of Texas Archives, 1875 (Box 22, Folder 27)
- Family Correspondence, 1829-1894, undated; 3
  General condition: Good.
  This series contains letters and books exchanged between William Carey Crane and his immediate and extended family. The materials are organized by individual.
  - Letterbook: William Carey Crane to Alcesta Flora Galusha, 1834-1840 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Letterbook: William Carey Crane to Jane Louisa Wright, 1840-1844 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Letterbook: Alcesta Flora Galusha to William Carey Crane, 1834-1840 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Letterbook: Jane Louisa Wright to William Carey Crane, 1841-1842 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Letterbook: Jane Louisa Wright to Alcesta Flora Galusha, 1835-1840 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Sallie Shepherd Anderson, 1845-1849 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Sallie Shepherd Anderson, 1850-1851 March (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Sallie Shepherd Anderson, 1851 April-1852 April (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Sallie Shepherd Anderson, 1852 May-1853 April (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Sallie Shepherd Anderson, 1853 June-1855 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Belle Crane Fleet, 1880-1881 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Galusha Family, 1829-1837 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Galusha Family, 1838-1839 April (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Galusha Family, 1839 May-December (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Galusha Family, 1840 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Galusha Family, 1841-1857 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Galusha Family, 1858-1884 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - C.J. and R. Shepherd, 1866-1879 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Elizabeth and G.B. Steel, 1842-1884 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Helen Wright, 1841-1843 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Helen Wright, 1845-1866 January (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Helen Wright, 1866 August-1886, undated (Box 24, Folder 17)
  - Martha Wright, 1854, undated (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Alcesta Flora Crane and Annie Crane, 1840-1877 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Arthur Crane, 1875-1876 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Balfour Crane, 1874-1881 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Charlie Crane, 1873-1879 (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Charles T. and David R. Crane, 1844-1875 (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Elizabeth Crane, 1839-1843 (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - Elizabeth Crane, 1844-1856 (Box 24, Folder 25)
  - Fuller Crane, 1839-1842 June (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Fuller Crane, 1842 August-1866 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Fuller Crane, 1867-1870 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Fuller Crane, 1873-1875 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - George W. and Gordon Crane, 1844-1879 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Hallie, Henry, and J. M. Crane, 1846-1887 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Jane Louisa Wright Crane, 1842-1866 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Judson Crane, 1835-1840 February (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Judson Crane, 1840 May-1841 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Judson Crane, 1842-1854 July (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Judson Crane, 1854 August-1858 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Judson Crane, 1859-1866 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Judson Crane, 1867-1871 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Kate Crane, 1845-1849 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Kate Crane, 1850-1867 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Kate Crane, 1868-1875, undated (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Louisa, Lydia, Royston, R.M., and Tom Crane, 1864-1894 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - William Carey Crane, Sr., 1839-1840 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - William Carey Crane, Sr., 1840-1842 September (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - William Carey Crane, Sr., 1842 November-1855 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - William Carey Crane, Sr., 1856-1866 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - William Carey Crane, Sr., 1869-1884 (Box 25, Folder 22)
  - William Carey Crane, Jr.: Nephew, 1862-1864 (Box 25, Folder 23)
  - William Carey Crane, Jr.: Son, 1866-1869 January 17 (Box 25, Folder 24)
  - William Carey Crane, Jr.: Son, 1869 January 31-1875 May (Box 25, Folder 25)
  - William Carey Crane, Jr.: Son, 1875 October-1879 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  - William R. Crane, 1841-1847 (Box 25, Folder 27)
- Legal Documents, 1869-1885, undated; 4
  This series, consisting of one folder, contains three briefs pertaining to William Carey Crane’s presidency at Baylor.
  - Briefs, 1869-1885, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Financial Documents, 1809-1901, undated; 5
  - Financial Documents: Accounting Journal: Richmond, 1832 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Account Books, 1834-1858 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Subscription Book: Baylor University, 1866 (Folder 4)
  - Ledger, 1870-1871 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Ledger, 1871-1875 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Ledger, 1875-1878 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Ledger, 1878-1880 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Cash Book, 1864-1869 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda, 1865 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Accounts: Baylor University, 1866-1871 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Subscription List: The Baptist, 1844 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Deeds, 1876-1878 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Land Transactions, 1878-1901 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Crane Estate, 1862-1886 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Baylor University, 1863-1864 August (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Baylor University, 1864 September-1865 January (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Baylor University, 1865 February-1866 June 15 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Baylor University, 1866 June 19-December (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Baylor University, 1867-1868 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Baylor University, 1869-1883 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Baylor University, 1884, undated (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Baylor University, undated (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Receipts: General, 1862-1866 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Receipts: General, 1867 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Receipts: General, 1868-1872 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Receipts: General, 1875-1883, undated (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - General, 1809-1832 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - General, 1833-1835 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - General, 1836-1838 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - General, 1839-1852 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - General, 1853-1857 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - General, 1860-1865 September (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - General, 1865 December-1866 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - General, 1867-1868 April (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - General, 1868 July-1873 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - General, 1874-1879 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - General, 1880-1888 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - General: (1 of 2), undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - General: (2 of 2), undated (Box 28, Folder 17)
- Literary Productions, 1827-1933, undated; 6
  This series contains diaries, sermons, scrapbooks, notebooks, and printed materials pertaining to Crane’s life, particularly his vocations of minister and teacher.
  - Literary Productions: Diary, 1833-1834 September (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Diary, 1834 November-1840 July 10 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Diary, 1840 June-1847 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1848-1853 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1854-1861 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1861-1869 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1866-1867 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Diary, 1876-1885 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Pocket Diary, 1885 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Chronicle, 1842 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Book: The Baptist, 1844-1845 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1834-1878 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1850-1885 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Bible, 1857 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: General, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Programs: Pageants, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: Baptism, 1839 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: Civil War, 1863-1924 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: General, 1865-1924 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Periodicals: The Baptist Evangelist, 1843-1844 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Periodicals: The Baptist Preacher, 1845 February (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals: The Freemasons’ Monthly Magazine, 1848 November (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Periodicals: General, 1872, 1883 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Recommendations: Schools Attended, 1832-1839 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Character Sketch: George Adams: “Life and Character of the Late William Crane”, 1868 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Oaths and Passes: Civil War, 1859-1872, undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Poetry: Winston Fontaine, 1864, undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Poetry: General, undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Art: Chinese Boats, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Art: Engravings: (1 of 5), undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Art: Engravings: (2 of 5), undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Art: Engravings: (3 of 5), undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Art: Engravings: (4 of 5), undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Art: Engravings: (5 of 5), undated (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Obituaries, 1865-1872, undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Articles: The Religious Herald: “Then, Not Now”, 1877-1878 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Articles: General, 1857, undated (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Autobiographical Materials: William Carey Crane, 1881, undated (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Resolutions: Independence Baptist Church, 1869, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Resolutions: United Friends of Temperance, 1872-1878 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Announcements: Baylor University, 1863-1874 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Announcements: Baylor University, 1876-1884 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Announcements: Baylor University, undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Lists: Students, 1874-1877 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Lists: Students, 1877-1883, undated (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Manuscripts: “Conditions at Baylor”: (1 of 2), 1863 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Manuscripts: “Conditions at Baylor”: (2 of 2), 1863 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts: “The Foolishness of Preaching”, undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Memoir: Alcesta Flora Crane, 1841 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Journals: Alcesta Flora Crane, 1837-1840 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Journals: Jane Louisa Wright Crane, 1841-1842 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Certificates: Masons, 1869-1882 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Certificates: General, 1858-1876 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Manual: Columbus Baptist Church: Mississippi, undated (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Contract: Mount Lebanon University, 1862, undated (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Advertisements: (1 of 2), undated (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Advertisements: (2 of 2), undated (Folder 19)
  - Transcriptions: Baylor University: (1 of 3), 1863-1868, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Transcriptions: Baylor University: (2 of 3), 1863-1868, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Transcriptions: Baylor University: (3 of 3), 1863-1868, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Records: Columbus Baptist Church: Mississippi, 1840-1859, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Literary Extracts: Jane Louisa Wright Crane, 1831-1833 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Literary Extracts: Jane Louisa Wright Crane, 1841 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Essay: Gordon Crane: “Love of Country”, 1874 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Essay: William Carey Crane: “Proofs of the Inspiration of the Scriptures”: (1 of 2), undated (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Essay: William Carey Crane: “Proofs of the Inspiration of the Scriptures”: (2 of 2), undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Essay: William Carey Crane: “Summary of Condition of Affairs at Baylor”, 1863 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Essay: William Carey Crane: “The Rational and the Supernatural in Religion”, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Book: William Carey Crane: The Foolishness of Preaching, 1853 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Book: Reverend T.H. Gallaudet: The Memorandum, 1835 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Book: Joseph Longking: Questions on the Gospels, 1842 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Book: Samuel Wilkeson: The American Colonies in Liberia, 1839 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Crane Estate, 1885-1894 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Louisiana Baptist Convention: (1 of 2), 1855-1862, undated (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Reports: Louisiana Baptist Convention: (2 of 2), 1855-1862, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Reports: Maryland State Colonization Society, 1839 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Broadsides, 1848-1877 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Circulars: Semple Broaddus College, 1856-1857, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Circulars: General, 1853-1873 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Circulars: General, 1873-1881 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Circulars: General, 1881-1887, undated (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Auxiliary Bible Society, 1838, undated (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Band of Hope: (1 of 2), 1875 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Band of Hope: (2 of 2), 1875 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: Montgomery Baptist Church, 1839-1841 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Photocopies: Montgomery Baptist Church, 1839-1841 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: R.W. Grand Lodge, 1858 (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - Directory: Scripture, 1861-1863 (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - Inventory: Mount Lebanon Baptist Church, 1863 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Report Cards: Hallie and Royston Crane, 1878-1882 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Tract: “Bible Catechism”, 1882 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Gradebook, 1851-1856 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Gradebook, 1852 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Catalogs: Mississippi Female College, 1855 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Catalogs: Mount Lebanon University, 1858-1862 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Catalogs: Mount Pleasant Classical Institution, 1827-1831 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Catalogs: Semple Broaddus College and Soule University, 1857, 1880 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Catalogs: University of Virginia and Western Baptist Theological Institute, 1846, 1879 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Register: Baylor University, 1867 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Register: Baylor University, 1876 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Register: Baylor University, 1878-1879 (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Register: Baylor University, 1879-1881 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Register: Baylor University, 1879-1885 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Register: Books, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Register: Mount Pleasant Classical Institution, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Register: Sermons in Published Works, 1851 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: Letter to Andrew Jackson, 1833 February 13 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: Proclamation, 1842 May 24 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Biographical Materials: Sam Houston: General, 1860-1862 (Box 37, Folder 8)